Oliver Bell

github.com/freshollie · obell.dev

A British computer programmer with 4 years of industry experience and a First Class BSc (Hons) in Computer Science. Specialises in full-stack software engineering. Expertise in designing and writing, tested, maintainable, and distributed software in many languages.

Employment

Bulb Energy LTD, London, UK

Software Engineer III (November 2020 - Present)

- Delivered several medium size projects within multiple teams, working with product managers and other engineers to complete the work.
- Work with React, TypeScript, NodeJS, GraphQL, Postgres, Kubernetes, GCP, Pub Sub
- Currently on the Debt Collection team, working on Dunning processes, Account harvesting, and creating ways to help members repay debt.

YOOX Net-a-Porter Group, London, UK

Software Engineer (May 2019 - November 2020)

- · Worked on a team developing internal apps with full-stack JavaScript/TypeScript
- Specialised in writing functional React, using styled-components, GraphQL for local state and network, and graphql-codegen to enforce types between front and backend.
- Designed and wrote AWS Serverless functions to ingest millions of product images
- Pushed for and implemented a monorepo based architecture for the team

Alelion Energy Systems GmbH, Munich, Germany

Software Engineer (August 2017 - September 2018)

- · Developed HA software for their distributed energy storage platform
- Worked with Docker, Python, TypeScript, C++, and Java
- Wrote their main time-series API which used Scylla (cassandra) for a data backend
- Designed and wrote an orchestrator for dynamic service deployment to a docker swarm
- · Worked as lead in a small team to re-write their main "Control-Center" UI in Angular 6
- Designed and implemented many microservices to split-up their UI backend

IndiCater Software LTD, Henley-On-Thames, UK

Intern Software Developer (July 2014 - August 2014) (July 2015 - September 2015)

- Developed web-based software used for the management of back-of-house catering
- Wrote server-side VBscript, and frontend javascript

Tech



Interests

- Programming (since 2012)
- FPV Miniquad Racing
- Reverse engineering
- Free Software
- DevOps
- Skiing
- Film-making
- Electronics

Part-time

- Delaware North (2018-2019)
- Compass (2016-2017)
- McDonalds (2013-2017)

Libraries

- jest-dynalite
- abridge
- shuttle-xpress-android

Education

First class BSc (Hons) Computer Science Coventry University 2015 - 2019

Computing A Level (B) Computing GCSE (A) Maths A Level (C) Maths GCSE (A*)

Projects

Betaflight Configurator - github.com/freshollie/fresh-configurator

I am in the process of writing an application to configure drone flight controllers over USB. This required writing; a parser to communicate with the flight controller, an api to decode and encode data for the flight controller, a GraphQL schema to make reasoning with the data easier, and an Electron application written in React. All written with TypeScript for full type coverage. The project is structured as a monorepo, and the generic parts of the application are available on NPM: npm.im/org/betaflight

jest-dynalite - github.com/freshollie/jest-dynalite

Whilst developing with AWS's dynamodb, I realised that creating tests against a real database would make writing queries which interact with Dynamodb much faster. After searching, there were not any libraries which suited the purpose I was looking for, so I built my own. The library currently has 15k+ weekly NPM downloads and 100+ GitHub stars.